## Shweta Sawant

501, Asha Residency, Indore (M.P.) Email: shwetasawant2794@gmail.com, Phone: (M) +91 9981553490

## Senior Software Developer at HSBC

I am working as a Senior Software Developer having 5.9+ years of experience in Information Technology and IT industry through all software development phases primarily 3+ years of experience in backend application development using Java.

I have 1.5 years of experience in test automation using serenity framework and 1 year of experience in manual testing. Being a part of scrum team I have also explored the requirement analysis phase till delivering the requirements.

#### **Skils**

- Java
- SpringBoot
- Serenity
- Jenkins
- RSA
- Domain

- Oracle Sql
- CSS3
- BDD
- Git-Hub
- JIRA
- HTML5
- Java Spring
- MVC
- Hibernate
- postman
- TDD
- GCP

- Micro-service
- Windows
- Eclipse
- Intellij
- Soap UIDDD

# **Core Competencies**

- Working on Infrastructure as a code.
- Multiskilling Core Java, Data Management,
- Hands on experience in implementing an DevOps Pipeline using Git and CI/CD tools set.
- Debugging and Error Handling using Splunk, PCF and WinCP.
- Working on SQL Queries.
- Working on Java inheritance, Abstract classes, oops concepts & Multithreading

### Project

Organization: HSBC (Hyderabad and Pune)

**Project**: Customer Due Diligence (CDD)

Domain: Banking

**About CDD**: CDD is an application which collects the information of customer in the branch of Bank and helps to complete the review of the customer based on risks.

### Experience

**Software Developer (2018 - till date):-** 3+ years of experience in core development of the application in CDD.

Automation Tester (June 2016-2018):- Worked as an automation using serenity framework in CDD.

Manual tester (2015-June 2016):- Worked as a manual tester in CDD.

### Education

- BSC (CS) with 76.9% class from Shri Vaishnav Institute of Management, DAVV university, Indore.
- Higher secondary with 78.8% from M.P board.
- High School with 83.6% from M.P. board

### **Achievements**

- Recognized by HSBC India for being in list of Top 20 Engineers.
- Rewarded by HSBC as a Star performer of the team.

### **Personal Information**

Date of Birth: 27th March 1995Languages Known: English, Hindi

### Declaration

I hereby declare that all the information provided above is true to the best of my knowledge.

**Place:** Pune

**Date:** 03/07/2021

(Shweta Sawant)